reformjudaism.org 2017-12-21

# Privacy Statement | URJ

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Statement describes the types of information Union for Reform Judaism (“URJ”) collects from and about you when you visit the URJ (“we,” or “our”) website or affiliated websites, listed in Appendix A below, our presence on social media (including Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Flickr, YouTube, LinkedIn, and Instagram), and any domains and online presences acquired in the future (collectively referred to as the “Site”),

This Privacy Statement, governed by our [Terms and Conditions](http://urj.org/terms) also explains how URJ may use and disclose such information, as well as your ability to control certain uses of it. By using the Site, you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Statement. If you do not, please do not use the Site.

#### Information Collection

**Information You Provide**

URJ collects personal information from you when you choose to share it with us. This may include when you use our Site, create an online account with us, create a camp registration profile with us, make a purchase, request information from us, sign up for newsletters or our email list, use our service, participate in a survey or promotion, or otherwise contact us. The personal information we collect may include your name, address, email address, or telephone number. If you register for camp with us or seek to work as a camp staff member, the personal information we collect may include a screen or user name, Instant Messaging User ID, photos, user-uploaded videos, social security number, government-issued ID number (e.g. Driver’s License), date of birth, or personal health information. If you make a purchase from us or make a donation, we may collect a credit/debit card number or other financial information.

**_Information You Provide Through Social Media_**

You may be required to provide certain personal information to create your URJ account or to receive certain offers. If you use a third party login to create your account (such as Facebook Connect) or otherwise link to us, we may receive certain information about you from the third party (such as a social network) based on your registration and privacy settings on those third party services.

**Information Automatically Collected**

We may use cookies, HTML tracking information, or other technologies to collect certain information about visitors to our Site and interactions with our emails and online advertisements, and to allow URJ to keep track of analytics and certain statistical information which enables URJ to improve its Site and provide you with more relevant content and advertising on our Site and other sites.

For example, we may automatically collect certain non-personal information from you, including but not limited to your browser type, device type, operating system, unique device identifier of any of your computer(s) or device(s) that are used to access the Site, software version, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, geolocation, phone model, phone operating system, and the domain name from which you accessed the Services. We also may collect information about your use of the Site, including the date and time you visit the Site, the areas or pages of the Site that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the Site, the number of times you return to the Site, other click-stream or site usage data, emails that you open, forward or click-through to our Site, and other sites that you may visit.

**_Third Party Service Providers_**

We may use third party service providers to support our Site or Apps. Some of these service providers may use technology such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or Flash cookies to receive, collect, and store information on our behalf.

**_Third Party Analytic Technologies_**

Our third party analytics and advertising service providers may also use technology such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or Flash cookies. We use third party analytics and advertising tools (including Google Analytics, Bing Webmaster Tools, Facebook’s Marketing APIs, Twitter Analytics, YouTube Analytics, and Sprinklr) that may automatically collect non-personal information from you when you interact with our Site, advertising, and social media. The Google Analytics features we use include Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, DoubleClick Platform Integrations, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. This non-personal information is collected through the use of first party cookies, third party cookies, and web beacons. The information collected may include IP address, the website you came from (known as the referring URL), the type of browser, device and operating system you use, the time and date of access, the pages you visit within our Site (and the order in which you visit them), geographic information, and other information that does not personally identify you. This information may be collected by and shared with our third party analytics and advertising service providers, including Google, Bing, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, and Sprinklr. These allow URJ, and our third party analytics and advertising service providers, to collect non-personal information about you and your use of our Site, advertising and social media.

**Information Collected From Other Sources**

We may obtain information about you from other sources, including social networks that you use to connect with URJ. This information may include name, user name, demographic information, updated address or contact information, interests, and publicly-observed data, such as from social media and online activity.

**Combination of Information**

We may combine the information we receive from and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through our Site, as well as information across other computers or devices that you may use, and from third party sources.

**Tracking Options and California Do Not Track Disclosures**

Certain parts of our Site require cookies. You are free to set your browser or operating system settings to limit certain tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features on the Site or take full advantage of all of our offerings. Please refer to your Web browser’s or operating system’s website or “Help” section for more information on how to delete and/or disable your browser or operating system from receiving cookies or controlling your tracking preferences.

Our system may not respond to Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies, click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) and [here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

#### Information Use

URJ may use the information we collect from and about you for any of the following purposes:

  * To respond to your inquiries, contact, and communicate with you;
  * To process payment card transactions for services you purchased from us;
  * To enable camp registrations for campers and camp staff;
  * To contact you with information, newsletters and promotional materials from URJ or on behalf of our partners and affiliates
  * To review the usage and operations of our Site and improve our content and services;
  * To provide you with customized Site content on the Site, or via email;
  * To contact you with information, newsletters and promotional materials from URJ or on behalf of our partners and affiliates;
  * To contact you when necessary;
  * To use your data in an aggregated non-specific format for analytical and demographic purposes;
  * To address problems with the Site or our business;
  * To protect the security or integrity of the Site;
  * As otherwise described to you at the point of data collection; and
  * To use and disclose your credit/debit card information only to process payments and prevent fraud

Additionally, if you use the Site to connect with third party services you authorize us to use information from and about you, on your behalf, to interact with these third party services based on your requests.

#### Information Sharing

URJ may disclose the information we collect from and about you as follows: (1) with affiliated organizations; (2) to our third party service providers that provide business, professional or technical support functions for us, including to the extent necessary or desirable to complete your transaction; (3) as necessary if we believe that there has been a violation of the URJ Terms of Use or of our rights or the rights of any third party; (4) to respond to judicial process or provide information to law enforcement or regulatory agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; and (5) as described to you at the point of collection.

URJ may also share aggregate or anonymous non-personal information with third parties for their marketing or analytics uses.

Also, URJ may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of our business. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information we have collected about you may be transferred to such entity. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, such information may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through this Site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

#### Service Providers

URJ may contract with third party service providers to perform functions related to the Site. These service providers will have access to your information needed to perform their business functions, but we do not permit them to use or share that information for other purposes.

#### Links to Other Websites

The Site may have links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the practices of such sites.

#### Public Forums

Any information you may disclose on our Site, in blogs, on message boards, in chat rooms, or on other public areas on the Site or other third-party websites that this Site may link to, becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas.

#### Children's Privacy

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Site to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen. If URJ learns that a child under the age of thirteen has provided personally identifiable information to the Site, it will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from its files.

#### Data Security

We have taken certain physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard the information we collect from and about our customers and Site visitors. While we make every effort to help ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee our security measures.

When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card information) on our forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

#### Data Storage

Your personal information is stored on servers in the United States; however, some of our brands, subsidiaries, organizations, and Service Providers may store information on servers hosted in other countries. As such, your personal information may be subject to the laws of other countries, where the data protection and other laws may differ from those of the United States. Your personal information may be disclosed in response to inquiries or requests from government authorities or to respond to judicial process in the countries in which we operate.

#### Access to Your Personal Information

To update your information stored by URJ, you may sign in to your account and update your personal information.

#### If You Have Questions

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or the practices described herein, you may contact us at 212-650-4000 or [urj@urj.org](mailto:urj@urj.org).

#### User's Acceptance of This Privacy Statement

By visiting the Site, you signify your acceptance to the terms of URJ’s Privacy Statement. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Statement, please do not use the Site.

#### Revisions to This Statement

URJ reserves the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add, remove, or otherwise revise portions of this Privacy Statement at any time. When we do, we will post the change(s) on the Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to these terms means you accept these changes. If we change the Privacy Statement in a material way, we will provide appropriate notice to you.

**Effective Date: June 2, 2017**

**Appendix A:**

**Websites:**

Urj.org

ReformJudaism.org

ReformJudaismmag.org

Ccrj.ca

Rac.org

Urjyouth.org

NFTY.org

Jacobscamp.org

Eisnercamp.org

Cranelakecamp.org

Campharlam.org

Campgeorge.org

Guci.org

Osrui.org

Campcoleman.org

Campkalsman.org

Campnewman.org

Greene.org

Kutzcamp.org

6pointssports.org

6pointsscitech.org

Par.nfty.org

Mar.nfty.org

Ger.nfty.org

Sar.nfty.org

Car.nfty.org

Nar.nfty.org

Str.nfty.org

So.nfty.org

Sw.nfty.org

Nw.nfty.org

No.nfty.org

Ne.nfty.org

Nel.nfty.org

Socal.nfty.org

Cwr.nfty.org

mi.nfty.org

mv.nfty.org

ov.nfty.org

mitzvahcorps.org

hellerhigh.org

nftyisrael.org

northeastjewishteens.org

urjnortheastcamps.org

justactnyc.org

nftyconvention.org

campjenny.nfty.org

nftysummer.org

arza.org
